

Nitin Kumar Metiyan

Software Engineer with more than 2.5 years of industrial experience. Full Stack Java Developer and an enthusiastic competitive programmer. Have experience in developing robust business level code, design & development of mobile apps and websites, back-end systems, micro-services, rest API, etc., for enterprise.

nitink386@gmail.com

Karnataka, Bengaluru, India

linkedin.com/in/Mr-Nex

7017466439

portfolio.mr-nex.vercel.app/

www.codechef.com/users/nex

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Paytm

11/2021 - Present

- Being a part of the Paytm Payment Gateway team, working on Java spring boot and sofa framework. Handling micro services,
- Coordinating with different teams for carrying out tasks related to end to end development of products.

Systems Engineer (Java Developer)

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd

06/2019 - 10/2021

Benaaluru, Karnataka

- Designed & developed the back-end systems in Java Spring framework, microservices by writing production level code for end to end development of products.
- Primary Developer/Owner of **Product Discount Management** system (Tata Sky).
- Developed RESTful APIs with JWT authentication for TRAI's new Channel Selector App. (Got a TCS Spot Award for this)
- Created a CR Management Tool for team. (Got another TCS Spot Award for this)

Android Development Internship

TexoPanda LLP

07/2018 - 08/2018

Benaaluru, Karnataka

7.3 CGPA

- Created an Event Management App from scratch.
- Worked on UI/UX in Android Studio and back-end using Google Firebase.
- Managed a team of 4 developers.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Uptime Tracker (Spring MVC)

- Rest API to trigger simultaneous requests and generate response in order to find - uptime/downtime, average response time, etc., of any website.

Mega BITE

Fully functional online food ordering app with user account management on Google Firebase.

Complete Fitness - Android App

Perfect fitness guide.

Complete Fitness - Website

- Everything related to Workout & Diet with illustrative GIFs, user account & session management, etc.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Technology

08/2015 - 05/2019 - Computer Science & Engineering

College Of Engineering Roorkee

SKILLS



LEARNING & INTERESTS

Competitive Programming, Problem Solving 🗷

4 * Coder at CodeChef (Highest rating - 1811) | 6 * DS Algo Problem Solver at HackerRank | LeetCode (highest rating- 1586)

CERTIFICATES

Java (07/2016 - Present)

CETPA Infotech Pvt Ltd in Collaboration with Oracle

Android Development (08/2018 - Present)

React Developer (08/2020 - Present)

LinkedIn Learning

AWS For Developers (07/2020 - Present)

LinkedIn Learning

ACHIEVEMENTS

Got two "On The Spot" awards in TCS for my work performance and problem solving capabilities.

Have created an effort tracking tool, which is being used by all teams mapped to my project in TCS

SOFTWARES

